<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CLI Usage on hostctl</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/</link><description>Recent content in CLI Usage on hostctl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>guumaster</copyright><atom:link href="https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>add</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/add/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/add/</guid><description>hostctl add Add content to a profile in your hosts file.
Synopsis Reads from a file and set content to a profile in your hosts file. If the profile already exists it will be added to it.
hostctl add [profiles] [flags] Options -f, --from string file to read -h, --help help for add -w, --wait duration Enables a profile for a specific amount of time. (example: 5m, 1h) (default -1ns) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>add domains</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/add_domains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/add_domains/</guid><description>hostctl add domains Add content in your hosts file.
Synopsis Set content in your hosts file. If the profile already exists it will be added to it.
hostctl add domains [profile] [domains] [flags] Options -h, --help help for domains --ip string domains ip (default &amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot;) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) -w, --wait duration Enables a profile for a specific amount of time.</description></item><item><title>backup</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/backup/</guid><description>hostctl backup Creates a backup copy of your hosts file
Synopsis Creates a backup copy of your hosts file with the date in .YYYYMMDD as extension.
hostctl backup [flags] Options -h, --help help for backup --path string A path to save the backup (default &amp;quot;/home/runner/work/hostctl/hostctl&amp;quot;) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro Auto generated by spf13/cobra</description></item><item><title>disable</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/disable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/disable/</guid><description>hostctl disable Disable a profile from your hosts file.
Synopsis Disable a profile from your hosts file without removing it. It will be listed as &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; while it is disabled.
hostctl disable [profiles] [flags] Options --all Disable all profiles -h, --help help for disable --only Enable all other profiles -w, --wait duration Enables a profile for a specific amount of time (default -1ns) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>enable</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/enable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/enable/</guid><description>hostctl enable Enable a profile on your hosts file.
Synopsis Enables an existing profile. It will be listed as &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; while it is enabled.
hostctl enable [profiles] [flags] Options --all Enable all profiles -h, --help help for enable --only Disable all other profiles -w, --wait duration Enables a profile for a specific amount of time (default -1ns) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>list</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list/</guid><description>hostctl list Shows a detailed list of profiles on your hosts file.
Synopsis Shows a detailed list of profiles on your hosts file with name, ip and host name. You can filter by profile name.
The &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; profile is all the content that is not handled by hostctl tool.
hostctl list [profiles] [flags] Options -h, --help help for list Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>list disabled</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list_disabled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list_disabled/</guid><description>hostctl list disabled Shows list of disabled profiles on your hosts file.
Synopsis Shows a detailed list of disabled profiles on your hosts file with name, ip and host name.
hostctl list disabled [flags] Options -h, --help help for disabled Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl list - Shows a detailed list of profiles on your hosts file.</description></item><item><title>list enabled</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list_enabled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/list_enabled/</guid><description>hostctl list enabled Shows list of enabled profiles on your hosts file.
Synopsis Shows a detailed list of enabled profiles on your hosts file with name, ip and host name.
hostctl list enabled [flags] Options -h, --help help for enabled Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl list - Shows a detailed list of profiles on your hosts file.</description></item><item><title>remove</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/remove/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/remove/</guid><description>hostctl remove Remove a profile from your hosts file.
Synopsis Completely remove a profile content from your hosts file. It cannot be undone unless you have a backup and restore it.
If you want to remove a profile but would like to use it later, use &amp;lsquo;hosts disable&amp;rsquo; instead.
hostctl remove [profiles] [flags] Options --all Remove all profiles -h, --help help for remove Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>remove domains</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/remove_domains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/remove_domains/</guid><description>hostctl remove domains Remove domains from your hosts file.
Synopsis Completely remove domains from your hosts file. It cannot be undone unless you have a backup and restore it.
hostctl remove domains [profile] [domains] [flags] Options -h, --help help for domains Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl remove - Remove a profile from your hosts file.</description></item><item><title>replace</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/replace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/replace/</guid><description>hostctl replace Replace content to a profile in your hosts file.
Synopsis Reads from a file and set content to a profile in your hosts file. If the profile already exists it will be overwritten.
hostctl replace [profile] [flags] Options -f, --from string file to read -h, --help help for replace Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro Auto generated by spf13/cobra</description></item><item><title>restore</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/restore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/restore/</guid><description>hostctl restore Restore hosts file content from a backup file.
Synopsis Reads from a file and replace the content of your hosts file.
WARNING: the complete hosts file will be overwritten with the backup data.
hostctl restore [flags] Options --from string The file to restore from -h, --help help for restore Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro Auto generated by spf13/cobra</description></item><item><title>status</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/status/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/status/</guid><description>hostctl status Shows a list of profile names and statuses on your hosts file.
Synopsis Shows a list of unique profile names on your hosts file with its status.
The &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; profile is always on and will be skipped.
hostctl status [profiles] [flags] Options -h, --help help for status Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro Auto generated by spf13/cobra</description></item><item><title>sync</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync/</guid><description>hostctl sync Sync some system IPs with a profile.
Synopsis Reads IPs and names from some local system and sync it with a profile in your hosts file.
Options -h, --help help for sync -w, --wait duration Enables a profile for a specific amount of time (default -1ns) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro hostctl sync docker - Sync your Docker containers IPs with a profile.</description></item><item><title>sync docker</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync_docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync_docker/</guid><description>hostctl sync docker Sync your Docker containers IPs with a profile.
Synopsis Reads from Docker the list of containers and add names and IPs to a profile in your hosts file.
hostctl sync docker [profile] [flags] Options -d, --domain string domain where your docker containers will be added (default &amp;quot;loc&amp;quot;) -h, --help help for docker --network string Filter containers from a specific network Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>sync docker-compose</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync_docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/sync_docker-compose/</guid><description>hostctl sync docker-compose Sync your docker-compose containers IPs with a profile.
Synopsis Reads from a docker-compose.yml file the list of containers and add names and IPs to a profile in your hosts file.
hostctl sync docker-compose [profile] [flags] Options --compose-file string path to docker-compose.yml -d, --domain string domain where your docker containers will be added (default &amp;quot;loc&amp;quot;) -h, --help help for docker-compose --network string Filter containers from a specific network --prefix keep project name prefix from domain name --project-name string docker compose project name Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists.</description></item><item><title>toggle</title><link>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/toggle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guumaster.github.io/hostctl/docs/cli-usage/toggle/</guid><description>hostctl toggle Change status of a profile on your hosts file.
Synopsis Alternates between on/off status of an existing profile.
hostctl toggle [flags] Options -h, --help help for toggle -w, --wait duration Toggles a profile for a specific amount of time (default -1ns) Options inherited from parent commands -c, --column strings Column names to show on lists. comma separated --host-file string Hosts file path (default &amp;quot;/etc/hosts&amp;quot;) --no-color force colorless output -o, --out string Output type (table|raw|markdown|json) (default &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;) -q, --quiet Run command without output --raw Output without borders (same as -o raw) SEE ALSO hostctl - Your dev tool to manage /etc/hosts like a pro Auto generated by spf13/cobra</description></item></channel></rss>